https://www.automess.de/en/privacy-policy

1. An overview of data protection
General information
The following information will provide you with an easy to navigate overview
of what will happen with your personal data when you visit our website. The
term “personal data” comprises all data that can be used to personally
identify you. For detailed information about the subject matter of data
protection, please consult our Data Protection Declaration, which we have
included beneath this copy.
Data recording on our website
Who is the responsible party for the recording of data on this website (i.e. the “controller”)
The data on this website is processed by the operator of the website, whose
contact information is available under section “Information Required by Law”
on this website.
How do we record your data
We collect your data as a result of your sharing of your data with us. This
may, for instance be information you enter into our contact form.
Our IT systems automatically record other data when you visit our website.
This data comprises primarily technical information (e.g. web browser,
operating system or time the site was accessed). This information is recorded
automatically when you access our website.
What are the purposes we use your data for
A portion of the information is generated to guarantee the error free
provision of the website. Other data may be used to analyse your user
patterns.
What rights do you have as far as your information is concerned
You have the right to receive information about the source, recipients and
purposes of your archived personal data at any time without having to pay a
fee for such disclosures. You also have the right to demand that your data are
rectified, blocked or eradicated. Please do not hesitate to contact us at any
time under the address disclosed in section “Information Required by Law” on
this website if you have questions about this or any other data protection
related issues. You also have the right to log a complaint with the competent
supervising agency.
Moreover, under certain circumstances, you have the right to demand the
restriction of the processing of your personal data. For details, please
consult the Data Protection Declaration under section “Right to Restriction of
Data Processing.”
Analysis tools and tools provided by third parties
There is a possibility that your browsing patterns will be statistically
analysed when your visit our website. Such analyses are performed primarily
with cookies and with what we refer to as analysis programmes. As a rule, the
analyses of your browsing patterns are conducted anonymously; i.e. the
browsing patterns cannot be traced back to you. You have the option to object
to such analyses or you can prevent their performance by not using certain
tools. For detailed information about this, please consult our Data Protection
Declaration below.
You do have the option to object to such analyses. We will brief you on the
objection options in this Data Protection Declaration.
2. General information and mandatory information
Data protection
The operators of this website and its pages take the protection of your
personal data very seriously. Hence, we handle your personal data as
confidential information and in compliance with the statutory data protection
regulations and this Data Protection Declaration.
Whenever you use this website, a variety of personal information will be
collected. Personal data comprises data that can be used to personally
identify you. This Data Protection Declaration explains which data we collect
as well as the purposes we use this data for. It also explains how, and for
which purpose the information is collected.
We herewith advise you that the transmission of data via the Internet (i.e.
through e-mail communications) may be prone to security gaps. It is not
possible to completely protect data against third party access.
Information about the responsible party (referred to as the “controller” in the GDPR)
The data processing controller on this website is:
E-mail: info@automess.de
The controller is the natural person or legal entity that single-handedly or
jointly with others makes decisions as to the purposes of and resources for
the processing of personal data (e.g. names, e-mail addresses, etc.).
Revocation of your consent to the processing of data
A wide range of data processing transactions are possible only subject to your
express consent. You can also revoke at any time any consent you have already
given us. To do so, all you are required to do is sent us an informal
notification via e-mail. This shall be without prejudice to the lawfulness of
any data collection that occurred prior to your revocation.
Right to object to the collection of data in special cases; right to object to direct advertising (Art. 21 GDPR)
In the event that data are processed on the basis of Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. e
or f GDPR, you have the right to at any time object to the processing of
your personal data based on grounds arising from your unique situation. This
also applies to any profiling based on these provisions. To determine the
legal basis, on which any processing of data is based, please consult this
Data Protection Declaration. If you log an objection, we will no longer
process your affected personal data, unless we are in a position to present
compelling protection worthy grounds for the processing of your data, that
outweigh your interests, rights and freedoms or if the purpose of the
processing is the claiming, exercising or defence of legal entitlements
(objection pursuant to Art. 21 Sect. 1 GDPR)
If your personal data is being processed in order to engage in direct
advertising, you have the right to at any time object to the processing of
your affected personal data for the purposes of such advertising. This also
applies to profiling to the extent that it is affiliated with such direct
advertising. If you object, your personal data will subsequently no longer
be used for direct advertising purposes (objection pursuant to Art. 21 Sect.
2 GDPR)
Right to log a complaint with the competent supervisory agency
In the event of violations of the GDPR, data subjects are entitled to log a
complaint with a supervisory agency, in particular in the member state where
they usually maintain their domicile, place of work or at the place where the
alleged violation occurred. The right to log a complaint is in effect
regardless of any other administrative or court proceedings available as legal
recourses.
Right to data portability
You have the right to demand that we hand over any data we automatically
process on the basis of your consent or in order to fulfil a contract be
handed over to you or a third party in a commonly used, machine readable
format. If you should demand the direct transfer of the data to another
controller, this will be done only if it is technically feasible.
SSL and/or TLS encryption
For security reasons and to protect the transmission of confidential content,
such as purchase orders or inquiries you submit to us as the website operator,
this website uses either an SSL or a TLS encryption programme. You can
recognise an encrypted connection by checking whether the address line of the
browser switches from “http://” to “https://” and also by the appearance of
the lock icon in the browser line.
If the SSL or TLS encryption is activated, data you transmit to us cannot be
read by third parties.
Information about, blockage, rectification and eradication of data
Within the scope of the applicable statutory provisions, you have the right to
at any time demand information about your archived personal data, their source
and recipients as well as the purpose of the processing of your data. You may
also have a right to have your data rectified, blocked or eradicated. If you
have questions about this subject matter or any other questions about personal
data, please do not hesitate to contact us at any time at the address provided
in section “Information Required by Law.”
Right to demand processing restrictions
You have the right to demand the imposition of restrictions as far as the
processing of your personal data is concerned. To do so, you may contact us at
any time at the address provided in section “Information Required by Law.” The
right to demand restriction of processing applies in the following cases:
In the event that you should dispute the correctness of your data archived
by us, we will usually need some time to verify this claim. During the time
that this investigation is ongoing, you have the right to demand that we
restrict the processing of your personal data.
If the processing of your personal data was/is conducted in an unlawful
manner, you have the option to demand the restriction of the processing of
your data in lieu of demanding the eradication of this data.
If we do not need your personal data any longer and you need it to exercise,
defend or claim legal entitlements, you have the right to demand the
restriction of the processing of your personal data instead of its
eradication.
If you have raised an objection pursuant to Art. 21 Sect. 1 GDPR, your
rights and our rights will have to be weighed against each other. As long as
it has not been determined whose interests prevail, you have the right to
demand a restriction of the processing of your personal data.
If you have restricted the processing of your personal data, these data – with
the exception of their archiving – may be processed only subject to your
consent or to claim, exercise or defend legal entitlements or to protect the
rights of other natural persons or legal entities or for important public
interest reasons cited by the European Union or a member state of the EU.
Rejection of unsolicited e-mails
We herewith object to the use of contact information published in conjunction
with the mandatory information to be provided in section “Information Required
by Law” to send us promotional and information material that we have not
expressly requested. The operators of this website and its pages reserve the
express right to take legal action in the event of the unsolicited sending of
promotional information, for instance via SPAM messages.
3. Recording of data on our website
Cookies
In some instances, our website and its pages use so-called cookies. Cookies do
not cause any damage to your computer and do not contain viruses. The purpose
of cookies is to make our website more user friendly, effective and more
secure. Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer and
stored by your browser.
Most of the cookies we use are so-called “session cookies.” They are
automatically deleted after your leave our site. Other cookies will remain
archived on your device until you delete them. These cookies enable us to
recognise your browser the next time you visit our website.
You can adjust the settings of your browser to make sure that you are notified
every time cookies are placed and to enable you to accept cookies only in
specific cases or to exclude the acceptance of cookies for specific situations
or in general and to activate the automatic deletion of cookies when you close
your browser. If you deactivate cookies, the functions of this website may be
limited.
Cookies that are required for the performance of the electronic communications
transaction or to provide certain functions you want to use (e.g. the shopping
cart function), are stored on the basis of Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR. The
website operator has a legitimate interest in storing cookies to ensure the
technically error free and optimised provision of the operator’s services. If
other cookies (e.g. cookies for the analysis of your browsing patterns) should
be stored, they are addressed separately in this Data Protection Declaration.
Server log files
The provider of this website and its pages automatically collects and stores
information in so-called server log files, which your browser communicates to
us automatically. The information comprises:
The IP address
This data is not merged with other data sources.
This data is recorded on the basis of Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR. The operator
of the website has a legitimate interest in the technically error free
depiction and the optimization of the operator’s website. In order to achieve
this, server log files must be recorded.
Contact form
If you submit inquiries to us via our contact form, the information provided
in the contact form as well as any contact information provided therein will
be stored by us in order to handle your inquiry and in the event that we have
further questions. We will not share this information without your consent.
Hence, the processing of the data entered into the contact form occurs
exclusively based on your consent (Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. a GDPR). You have the
right to revoke at any time any consent you have already given us. To do so,
all you are required to do is sent us an informal notification via e-mail.
This shall be without prejudice to the lawfulness of any data collection that
occurred prior to your revocation.
The information you have entered into the contact form shall remain with us
until you ask us to eradicate the data, revoke your consent to the archiving
of data or if the purpose for which the information is being archived no
longer exists (e.g. after we have concluded our response to your inquiry).
This shall be without prejudice to any mandatory legal provisions – in
particular retention periods.
Request by e-mail, telephone or fax
If you contact us by e-mail, telephone or fax, your request, including all
resulting personal data (name, request) will be stored and processed by us for
the purpose of processing your request. We do not pass these data on without
your consent.
The processing of these data is based on Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR, if your
request is related to the execution of a contract or if it is necessary to
carry out pre-contractual measures. In all other cases, the processing is
based on your consent (Article 6 (1) a GDPR) and/or on our legitimate
interests (Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR), since we have a legitimate interest in the
effective processing of requests addressed to us.
The data sent by you to us via contact requests remain with us until you
request us to delete, revoke your consent to the storage or the purpose for
the data storage lapses (e.g. after completion of your request). Mandatory
statutory provisions - in particular statutory retention periods - remain
unaffected.
4. Plug-ins and Tools
Google Web Fonts (local embedding)
This website uses so-called Web Fonts provided by Google to ensure the uniform
use of fonts on this site. These Google fonts are locally installed so that a
connection to Google’s servers will not be established in conjunction with
this application.
We use cookies Your experience on this site will be improved by allowing cookies. By continuing to browse our site you agree to our use of cookies and revised Privacy Policy.
Allow cookies
